Guide to the Henry Herbert Knibbs Papers, 1874-1945
Department of Special Collections
Henry Herbert Knibbs Papers,
1874-1945
Special Collections M0188
Knibbs, Henry Herbert, 1874-1945.
4 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Keith Lummis, 1969.
Biography
Writer of "western fiction." Born in Canada in 1874 and emigrated to California in 1910. Knibbs' novels are set in the West and in revolutionary Mexico. Died in 1945.
Scope and Content
Corresponence, documents, photographs and sketches, newspaper clippings, tearsheets, and Knibbs' death mask. The areas covered include works by Henry Knibbs, including novels, short stories and poetry; biographical data on Knibbs; and works by other authors.
Container List
- Section I: Works By Henry H. Knibbs.
  - Lists of works. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Unidentified. Carbon typescript, 25 pp. (pp. 6 - 30) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Carbon typescript, 20 pp.
  - Miscellaneous, c., 100 pp.
  - Untitled. Carbon typescript, 28 pp. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Carbon typescript, 13 pp., re old pioneer couple.
  - Archie, Typescript with autograph corrections, 12 pp. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Carbon typescript, 12 pp.
    (two different drafts)
  - Bedrock, Carbon typescript, 25 pp. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The Bee Keeper Of Arlington, Typescript, 16 pp. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Black Apache, Typescript with autograph corrections, 13 pp. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Typescript and two carbon typescript, 14 pp. each.
  - Typescript and carbon typescript, each, 21 pp.
    (three different drafts)
  - Black Lightning, Carbon typescript, 28 pp. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - A Boy I Knew (alternately titled, Ticket Of Leave Man). Unpublished autobiography, written shortly before Knibb's death in 1945 (approximately one-third complete at that time) and edited by Turbesé Lummis Fiske. Title page fragment
    - Early fragmentary drafts., typescript and carbon typescript, both with autograph corrections, 131 pp. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Knibb's original final draft, unedited.Typescript with autograph corrections, pp. 1 - 173. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Final Draft. Typescript, pp. 1 - 83 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Carbon typescript, pp. 84 - 275
    - Carbon typescript, pp. 84 - 201.
    - Revised final draft, with editor's explanatory note appearing for the first time, at p. 285. Carbon typescript, pp. 1 - 288. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Chinkapin, Carbon typescript, 20 pp. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Circulatin, Typescript, 28 pp. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Dead Or Alive, Typescript and carbon typescript, each 29 pp. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Five Miles To Perdition, Carbon typescript, 18 pp. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Typescript, 18 pp.
  - The Forty-Four Pocket Piece, Typescript with autograph corrections, 21 pp. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Ghost Horse, Carbon typescript, 24 pp. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Hic! Pericles, Fragmentary drafts, typescript with autograph corrections, 87 pp. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Carbon typescript, 34 pp.
  - Hunting Trouble, Carbon typescript, 19 pp. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Indigo Pete, Preferred., Fragmentary draft, carbon typescript with autograph corrections, 72 pp. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Fragmentary drafts, miscellaneous, 45 pp.
  - Typescript with autograph corrections, 97 pp.
  - Lily Sentence outline and fragmentary drafts, typescript and manuscript, with autograph corrections, 23 pp. (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - The Man Of the Whispering Spurs (co-authored with Turbesé Lummis Fiske)., Typescript, 246 pp. (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Nobody's Ghost, Carbon typescript, 20 pp. (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - The Other Valley, Carbon typescript, 27 pp. (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Outside the Law, Carbon typescript, 43 pp. (plus typescript pp. 39 - 43). (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Paul and Pierre, Typescript and carbon typescript, each 56 pp. (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Peanut and the Mebbyso Partners, Carbon typescript, 19 pp. (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Pecos Jim stories. Untitled, carbon typescript (partially typescript) 30 pp., consisting of several fragments. (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Untitled, carbon typescript (partially typescript), 37 pp.
  - Untitled, carbon typescript, 26 pp. (pp. 2 - 27).
    (Three different stories)
  - Peter and Pericles Carbon typescript, 21 pp. (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Pretty Good Man With a Gun Typescript and carbon typescript, each, 78 pp. (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Quon Yin and the Law, Typescript with autograph corrections, 10 pp. (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - The Rats' Nest, Typescript, 41 pp. (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - The Red Doctor's Prescription, Carbon typescript, 28 pp. (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - The Red Spot Carbon typescript, (two copies), 13 pp. (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Typescript with autograph corrections, 9 pp. (pp. 11 - 19).
  - Carbon typescript, 7 pp. (pp. 11 - 17).
  - Sandy Carbon typescript, 14 pp. (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Carbon typescript, 20 pp. (plus typescript of p. 20)
    (two different drafts).
  - Scoopy (co-authored with Turbesé Lummis Fiske) (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Fragmentary drafts, typescript and carbon typescript with autograph corrections, 64 pp.
    - First draft, typescript, 56 pp.
    - Final draft, typescript and carbon typescript, each 20 pp.
  - A Shot In the Dark, Typescript, 21 pp. (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Six Frames the Gang, Fragmentary drafts, typescript with autograph corrections, 99 pp (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Original final draft, typescript with autograph corrections, 45 pp.
  - Publisher's draft, carbon typescript, 62 pp.
  - Skood Rides His Luck, Typescript with autograph corrections, 19 pp. (pp. 6 - 24) (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Two carbon typescript, each, 8 pp. (pp. 19 - 26).
  - Slim Plays a Fast Game, Fragmentary draft, carbon typescript with autograph corrections, 7 pp. (pp.20-26) (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Carbon typescript, 29 pp.
  - Songs Of the Lost Frontier. Manuscript, typescript, and autograph corrected tearsheets, 46 pp., including the following (in this order): (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Stallions Of the Storm
      indicates additional copies and drafts are in the poetry general file, 5-54, 5-55.
    - Barrowlea
    - Nameless River
    - Dirge Of An Indian Mother
    - A Barb Of Spain
    - Marjorie Pickthal
    - The Silver-Shod
    - Chang Chung Chang
    - Lost Ledge
    - Illilouette
    - Outlaw (formerly Black Storm)
    - The Spanish Man
    - Legend Of Billy the Kid
    - Song Of the Mule
    - Manuel Escobar
    - Just Over the Border
    - Charley Lee
    - He'll Make a Hand
    - Morningstar
    - The Plains
    - Bill McGee
    - Benny Benito
    - Boomer Johnson
    - Walkin' John
    - Joe Biddle
    - Bill Tandy
    - The Bosky Steer
    - Mournful Joe (formerly, The Ballad Of Mournful Joe)
    - Tonga Bill
    - If a Horse Could Talk
    - The Bigelow Boys
    - That Was Maw
  - The Tenderfoot Steps In, Carbon typescript, 17 pp. (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Carbon typescript, 18 pp.
  - Typescript, 26 pp.
    (fragmentary drafts)
  - Tonto Basin Outlaw, Typescript, 34 pp. (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Tonto Keeps the Change, Typescript, 15 pp. (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Tonto Kid. Incomplete galley proof, 37 sheets. (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Town's End, Typescript and two carbon typescript, each 9 pp. (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Ulysses At the Gate, Typescript, 5pp. (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Vinegaroon and the Lamb St. John, Two carbon typescript, each 22pp. (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - What To Do? Walk, Typescript, 14 pp. (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Who Drinks the Water Of the Hassayampa..., Typescript with autograph corrections, 42 pp. (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Young Hardesty stories., Carbon typescript, 31 pp. (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Carbon typescript, 37 pp. ( Bedrock's Partner, Chapter 1)
  - Carbon typescript, 28 pp.
    (three different stories)
  - Zing, Carbon typescript, 16 pp. (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Poetry, General File, Untitled, A - E. Including manuscript, typescript, carbon typescript, and tearsheet, (some with autograph correction) of the following: (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Untitled, (37 pp.)
    - The Adventurer
    - An Mind Ye, Mither?
    - Apaloosie Bill
    - Arithmatic, See Wayfarer
    - At This Farewell
    - Ballad Of the Herd Boy
    - Ballad Of Billy the Kid; See also Folder 4 - 42.
    - Ballad Of Boot Hill
    - Balland Of the Broomtails
    - A Barb Of Spain; See also Folder 4 - 42.
    - Barrowlea; See also Folder 4 - 42.
    - Benny Benito; See Folder 4 - 42.
    - Betty Jane
    - The Bigelow Boys; See Folder 4 - 42.
    - Bill McGee; See also Folder 4 - 42.
    - Bill Tandy; See also Folder 4 - 42.
    - Black Storm; See also Folder 4 - 42.
    - Blue Gene
    - A Blue-Grass Colt
    - Boomer Johnson; See also Folder 4 - 42.
    - The Border Land
    - The Bosky Steer; See Folder 4 - 42.
    - Boss Of Cinder Town
    - A Brachycephalic Dome
    - Burro
    - A Braided Bridle
    - Chang Chung Chang; See also Folder 4 - 42.
    - Charley Lee; See also Folder 4 - 42.
    - Cheeopah
    - Cherokee Strip
    - Christmas, 1906
    - Cowboy, What You Doin' Here
    - The Day Of Nine Books
    - Dirge Of the Indian Mother; See also Folder 4 - 42.
    - Don Carlos
    - The Drums Of Spain
    - Dust Of Gold
    - End Of the Road
    - The Earth and Us
    - The Edge of Town
  - Poetry, General File, F - Z: (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Fane Arden
    - Faraday Bill
    - The Frontier Doc
    - The Fugitive
    - Gabriel's Border Patrol
    - Gambler's Choice
    - Gifts
    - The Golden Leopard
    - He'll Make A Hand; See Folder 4 - 42.
    - The Herd Boy, (xerox)
    - His Enemy
    - I Have Builded Me A Home
    - If A Horse Could Talk; See also Folder 4 - 42.
    - Illilouettee; See also Folder 4 - 42
    - In Gratitude
    - Inland
    - The Irate Pilgrim
    - Joe Biddle; See also 4 - 42.
    - Julia
    - Just Over the Border; See also Folder 4 - 42.
    - Layman's Dream
    - Legend Of Mournful Joe; See also Folder 4 - 42.
    - Legend Of Navajo
    - The Little People
    - Lost Gold
    - Lost Ledge; See Folder 4 - 42.
    - Lyric
    - Man O' War
    - The Man Upon the Way
    - Marjorie Pickthal; See also Folder 4 - 42.
    - Men Of My Country
    - A Meeting in Bret Harte's Country
    - Manuel Escobar; See Folder 4 - 42.
    - Morningstar; See also Folder 4 - 42.
    - Mudshell
    - The Mule
    - Nameless River; See also Folder 4 - 42.
    - Ode To Anesthesia - Our Lady Of Mercy
    - The Old Alcalde
    - The Old Buccaneer
    - Old Timer
    - The Optimist
    - Out There Somewhere
    - Out Where the West Belongs
    - The Plant of Sara
    - The Plant of the Athenian Woman
    - Plant of The Chinese Woman
    - Pine Tree Trail (Up Cuyamaca)
    - The Plains; See also Folder 4 - 42.
    - Powder Bill
    - Prevision
    - Rain Makers
    - Renegade
    - Reguiem
    - Ricardo
    - Roll a Rock Down
    - Roll On, Ole River
    - Sappho
    - Seldom Joe
    - Silent Joe
    - The Silver-Shod; See Folder 4 - 42.
    - Song Of Mora
    - Song Of the Mule; See Folder 4 - 42.
    - The Squire
    - The Spanish Man; See also Folder 4 - 42.
    - Stallion Gray
    - Stallions Of the Storm; See also Folder 4 - 42.
    - Temescal Of Cabezon
    - The Tenderfoot
    - That Was Maw; See also Folder 4 - 42.
    - That Lila Lee Mare
    - A Thousand Miles Or So
    - Tonga Bill; See Folder 4 - 42.
    - The Toughest Man In Town
    - Trail To Glory
    - Tree By the Window
    - The Two Saddles
    - Unidentified
    - Valley That God Forgot
    - Walkin' John; See also Folder 4 - 42.
    - Wanderer's Highway
    - Wayfarer
    - We Aim To Please
    - Wherever
    - Which Way Is the Wagon?
    - Wife of Bath
    - Wild Horses
    - The Wind
  - Notebooks Of Henry H. Knibbs. (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Including one on architecture; and one with start of autograph manuscript autobiography, 6 pp.
  - Miscellaneous notes and outlines, (c. 60 items). (Box 5, Folder 57)
- Section II: Correspondence.
  - General File, unidentified, A - M. Including letters to, from, or about the following: (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Unidentified, (27).
    - Adventure magazine, n.d., 1935 - 1951(50): See Folder 6 - 60.
    - AFG Literary Agency, 1937 - 1939(7): See Folder 6 - 61. Elmo, Ann
    - Allen, Jules, 1938.
    - American Society For the Prevention Of Cruelty To Animals, 1938(2).
    - Apikuni, 1932 - 1939, (2).
    - Arizona Daily Star, 1936.
    - Baccus, J. H., 1933.
    - Bailey, Ledyard M., n.d., 1932, (2).
    - Barlow, H.L., 1934.
    - Black Mountain Public Library, 1934.
    - Bliss, H.H., 1932.
    - Blue Book magazine, 1934 - 1935(2); See also McCall Corporation.
    - Borg, Carl Oscar, n.d.
    - Bosworth, Morris F., 1933.
    - Braley, Berton, n.d.
    - Bralliar, Floyd, n.d.
    - Briggs, L. B. R., 1932.
    - Brown, Laura L., 1931.
    - Brucato, Paul John, 1932.
    - Buckley, Thomas J., 1933.
    - Campbell, Maury B., 1940.
    - Carey, Oliver, 1944.
    - Chambrun, Jacques, 1931 - 1937(7): See Folder 6 - 62.
    - Chapman, C. R., 1934 - 1946, (4).
    - Chapman, Gerard, 1948, (2).
    - Chapman, John B., 1933.
    - Chapman, William Gerard: See Folder 6 - 63.
    - Coleman, Rufus A, 1931.
    - Costain, Thomas Bertram: See Folder 6 - 83.
    - The Country Gentleman, 1931 - 1944, (4).
    - Counts, Bee, 1937.
    - Crussell, Edward H., 1937, (2).
    - Curran, R. E., 1931.
    - Curtis, Brown, Ltd., 1949.
    - Dabbs, Mary C., n.d., (2).
    - Dakin, Rodney G., 1934 - 1938, (2).
    - Danburg, Walter Malcolm: See Folder 6 - 64.
    - Davis, J. Frank, 1932.
    - Davison, Marie A., n.d.
    - De Kalb, Frances Douglas, 1930 - 1946, (2).
    - Dodd, Mead, and Company, Inc., 1944.
    - Doubleday, Doran, and Co.,: See Folder 6 - 65.
    - Duckworth-Ford, Robert A.: See Folder 6 - 66.
    - E. P. Dutton and Co., Inc., 1948, (3).
    - Dyer, Frank L.: See Folder 6 - 67.
    - Dykes, J. C., 1942.
    - Editors Press Service Inc., 1945, (3).
    - Eldridge, Paul, 1932 - 1946, (3).
    - Famous Artists Corporation Agency, 1949.
    - Feature Fiction, Inc., n.d.
    - Foulke, Judy, 1933.
    - Frothingham, Robert: See Folder 6 - 68.
    - George J. Gala 1936
    - Gates, Arnold F., 1940.
    - Glassell, Steve A. 1930 - 1940, (3).
    - Greenslet, Ferris: See Folder 6 - 70.
    - Gould, Charles N., 1939.
    - Haraszthy, Helen, 1930.
    - Harper and Brothers, 1942.
    - Heckelmann, Charles N. 1948(2); See also Popular Library.
    - Hewett, ---, 1945.
    - Hoffman, Arthur Sullivant: See Folder 6 - 69.
    - Hoffman, Lincoln, 1935.
    - Hoofs and Horns, 1931.
    - Horn, Roy: See Folder 6 - 65.
    - Houghton, Mifflin, Co.: See Folder 6 - 70.
    - Hughes, Tom, n.d.
    - Jackson, Joseph Henry, 1931.
    - Kent, Ira Rich: See Folder 6 - 70.
    - Kent, Josephine MacPherson: See Folder 6 - 71.
    - Knibbs, Clyde E., 1938.
    - Knibbs, Ida Julia (wife of HHK): See Folder 6 - 72.
    - Knibbs, Olive (sister of HHK): See Folder 6 - 73.
    - Knibbs, Sara (mother of HHK): See Folder 6 - 74.
    - Ladies' Home Journal, 1933.
    - Lane, George W., 1933.
    - Larkin, Roosevelt, and Larkin, 1945.
    - Larremore, Thomas A., 1936.
    - Larsen, Hi, 1933 - 1940, (2).
    - Lincoln, Heleb L., 1938.
    - Lewis, Ned. O., 1938.
    - Lummis, Jordan: See Folder 6 - 75.
    - Lummis, Wilbur S., 1928.
    - Mac, Sandy: See Folder 6 - 76.
    - The Macaulay Company, publishers, 1932.
    - McCall Corporation, 1939 - 1944, (3).
    - Mackenzie, Flora, 1940.
    - McLain, ---, 1945, (4).
    - Macleish, Archibald C., n.d.
    - Macmillan Company, publishers, 1947.
    - Martin, Mrs. ---, 1948.
    - Maule, Harry Edward: See Folder 6 - 65.
    - Miller, Frank L., 1938.
    - Molyneux-Molony, John Le Baptiste, 1931, (2).
    - Mullins, Helene, n.d.
  - General File, N - Z, including letters to, from, or about, the following: (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Niles, M. A., 1933.
    - Palmerston, Colin C., n.d., 1930(2).
    - Correspondence re Pericles' Honeymoon error, 1933:See Folder 6 - 77.
    - Perry, Bliss: See Folder 6 - 78.
    - The Phantom Gypsy, 1933.
    - Phillips, John: See Folder 6 - 79.
    - Pocket Books, Inc., publishers, 1946, (7).
    - Popular Library, Inc., 1948, (4).
    - Random House, Inc., publishers: See Folder 6 - 80.
    - Reid, Edward C., 1938.
    - Rhodes, Eugene Manlove: See Folder 6 - 81.
    - Rhodes, Rosemary (Mrs. Eugene Manlove): See Folder 6 - 82.
    - Rifkin, Shepard, 1934.
    - Row, Peterson, and Company, 1951, (2).
    - Rowland, Mabel W., 1933, (3).
    - Ruis, M. P., 1933.
    - The Saturday Evening Post: See Folder 6 - 83.
    - Schaffer, Béla, n.d.,:See Folder 6 - 84.
    - Scott, Walter, 1937, (2).
    - Seffens, Jay W., 1940.
    - Sherwin, Sterling, 1936
    - Shippey, ---, 1946.
    - Short Stories magazine, 1937 - 1938, (3).
    - Simpson, W. H., 1930.
    - Skiff, Frederick Woodward, 1937.
    - Smith, H. Allen, 1944.
    - Street and Street, 1931 - 1944, (3).
    - Teaboldt, Harrie and Mae, n.d.:See Folder 6 - 85.
    - Teakle, Thomas, 1932, (3).
    - Thompson, L. S., 1933.
    - Thorne, Mary B., n.d., (2).
    - Ulrick, Robert, 1930.
    - Upton, J. Duane, 1939 - 1940, (2).
    - Van Der Veer, Judy: See Folder 6 - 86.
    - Ward, Fay, 1934.
    - Westerberg, Iwar Sigurd: See Folder 6 - 87.
    - Westerberg, Ralph, 1932.
    - Western Printing and Lithographing Company, 1948 - 1949, (12).
    - Western Livestock Journal, 1934 - 1935, (4).
    - Who's Who In the Western Hemisphere, 1943.
    - Winford Publications, Inc., 1935 - 1938, (2).
    - Winnek, E. V., 1943 - 1945, (2).
    - Yore, Clem: See Folder 6 - 88.
      ( Note: Dates listed are of first and last year, and are not inclusive Figures in parentheses indicate number of items; if no such figure is given, there is only one letter.
      Most letter of 1945, and all 1946 on, are to and from Turbesé Lummis Fiske, in her capacity as administratrix of Henry Knibb's estate.)
  - Adventure magazine, n.d., 1935 - 1951, (50). (Box 6, Folder 60)
    Bloomfield, Howard V. L.
  - AFG Literary Agency, 1937 - 1939, (7). (Box 6, Folder 61)
    Elmo, Ann.
  - Chambrun, Jacques, 1931 - 1937, (7). (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Chapman, William Gerard (1877 - 1945), 1933 - 1944, (14). (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Danburg, Walter Malcolm (1880 -), n.d., 1933 - 1940, (5). (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Doubleday, Doran, and Company, publishers, 1930 - 1935, (25). (Box 6, Folder 65)
    Horn, Roy.
    Maule, Harry Edward (1886 -).
  - Duckworth-Ford, Robert A., 1931 - 1944, (14). (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Dyer, Frank L., 1934. (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Frothingham, Robert, n.d., 1930 - 1937, (24). (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Hoffman, Arthur Sullivant (1876 -), 1930 - 1946, (6). (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Houghton, Mifflin, Company, n.d., 1929 - 1948, (50). (Box 6, Folder 70)
    Greenslet, Ferris (1875 -).
    Kent, Ira Rich (1876 -).
  - Kent, Josephine Mac Pherson, 1934 - 1935, (2). (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Knibbs, Ida Julia (HHK's wife), n.d., 1931 - 1938, (47). (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Knibbs, Olive (HHK's sister), n.d., (11). (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Knibbs, Sara (HHK's mother), n.d., (16). (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - Lummis, Jordan, 1936 - 1939, (3). (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - Mac, Sandy, n.d., 1935 - 1938, (8). (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - Correspondence re the error in Pericles Honeymoon, 1933(21). (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Perry, Bliss (1860 -), 1930 - 1939, (4). (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - Phillips, John, 1938, (2). (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - Random House, Incorporated, 1944 - 1945, (8). (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - Rhodes, Eugene Manlove (1869 - 1935), n.d., 1930 - 1931, (3). (Box 6, Folder 81)
  - Rhodes, Rosemary (Mrs. Eugene Manlove), 1929 - 1948, (13). (Box 6, Folder 82)
  - The Saturday Evening Post, 1932 - 1938, (21). (Box 6, Folder 83)
    Costain, Thomas Bertram (1885 -).
  - Schaffer, Béla, n.d., 1933 - 1937, (22). (Box 6, Folder 84)
  - Teaboldt, Harrie and Mae, n.d., 1919 - 1936, (10). (Box 6, Folder 85)
  - Van der Veer, Judy, n.d., 1922 - 1948, (25). (Box 6, Folder 86)
  - Westerberg, Iwar Sigurd (1874 -), 1934 - 1944, (54). (Box 6, Folder 87)
  - Yore, Clem (1875 - 1936), 1933 - 1934, (4). (Box 6, Folder 88)
- Section III: Documents.
  - General File, including: (Box 7, Folder 89)
    - HHK's parents marriage license and certificate, photostat.
    - Permit for removal for burial.
    - Immigration records of HHK's ancestors.
    - Internal Revenue Service forms, 1943.
    - Royalty statements, 1930 - 1944, (19).
    - Receipts, (2).
    - Will of Sara Knibbs, carbon.
    - Assignment of copyright for Fragile: Use No Hooks, April 1936.
    - Contract with the McCall Corporation for a short story, September 28, 1934.
    - "Circumstances under which Mr. Knibbs left ..."
- Section IV: Miscellany.
  - Biographical data on Henry Knibbs. (Box 7, Folder 90)
  - Photographs (21) and sketches (4). (Box 7, Folder 91)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1909 - 1945(c. 100); mostly on Henry Knibbs or reviews of his works. (Box 7, Folder 92)
  - Material read at Henry Knibbs's memorial service. (Box 7, Folder 93)
- Section V: Works By Others Than Henry Knibbs
  - Ford, Robert A. Duckworth, short stories, entitled: (Box 7, Folder 94)
    - Barbara Winter -- Straight Shooter, carbon typescript, 33 pgs.
    - The Brave Open Spaces, carbon typescript, 18 pgs.
    - The Tornado, typescript, 30 pgs.
  - Knibbs, Sara, autograph manuscript notebook 1929 - mostly impressions of books read; autograph manuscript recollections of family and historical events, 45 pp. (Box 7, Folder 95)
  - Knibbs, Sara, diary entitled, Next Reincarnation Or Perhaps, typescript, with autograph corrections, c. 200 pp. + "Sara's Journal", pen and ink drawings + typed poems (Box 7, Folder 96)
  - Sissons, Grace, And God So Near, typescript, manuscript, typescript carbon many with autograph corrections, includes drafts of chapters at various stages of completion - fragmentary, first draft, revised, and some final draft. Also included are numerous flase starts at chapters, some of whichwere later incorporated into completed chapters, (300 pp.). (Box 7, Folder 97)
  - Sissons, Grace, Mirage typescript, 25 pp. (Box 7, Folder 98)
- Section VI: Oversize
  - Death Mask of Henry Knibbs.
  - Carton of tearsheets and whole number periodicals, including the following:
    - (Stories and poems by Henry Knibbs) Whole Numbers:
      - The Amazing Tenderfoot Popular Magazine, 9/20/15,p. 1B.
      - Beef Popular Magazine, 11/20/19,p. 68.
      - Federal Man Short Stories, 9/25/37.p. 8.
      - The Lightnin Kid Western Book Magazine, 3/34,p. 4.
      - Noch-Tee's Daughter Popular Magazine,, 2/11/28,p. 50.
      - Outside the Law Adventure, p. 29.
      - Paydirt and Jailings Popular Magazine, 8/20/20,p. 93.
      - Pericles' Honeymoon Sat. Eve. Post, 8/19/33,p. 18.
      - The Real Romance Smith's Magazine, 8/11,p. 698.
      - Six Frames the Gang Adventure, 1/42,p. 15.
      - Sunny Mateel Popular Magazine, 5/7/15,p. 1.
      - That Colt Pericles Sat. Eve. Post, 5/21/32,p. 12.
      - Under the Joshua Tree Worthwhile, 5/28,pg. 4.
      - Why Pericles Sat. Eve. Post, 4/1/33,p. 24.
    - Tearsheets. Poems, unless otherwise indicated:
      - A Bronco With Shod Wings 11/25/21.
      - A Faith To Keep
      - A Minute With Popular Magazine, 7/2/29.
      - An Indian Purse 3/20/16.
      - Apaloosie Bill
      - Ballad of the Broomtails
      - The Barb of Spain Adventure, 2/15/30.
      - Beaverkill
      - The Big Man's Anathema Popular Magazine, 3/17/16.
      - Bill Melody
      - Bill Tandy Short Stories, 9/10/29.
      - Bo' Jou', Marie Popular Magazine, 10/20/15.
      - Boomer Johnson Short Stories, 1/10/30, pg. 137.
      - The Borderland
      - Boss of Cindertown
      - Boss of the Silver Queen
      - The Buckskin of Meskite
      - California
      - Chance Popular Magazine, 3/20/16.
      - Comanche Bend
      - Cowboy, What You Doin' Here?
      - Fragile, Use No Hooks Short Stories, 4/10/29.
      - The Frontier Doe Short Stories, 8/10/30.